### Contact

fisher.472@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jasonjfisher (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Healthcare

Healthcare Information Technology Nursing

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

#### **CCRN**

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support Experienced Provider (ACLS)

Registered Nurse

**NIHSS** 

Registered Nurse

### Honors-Awards

Ohio Nurse of the Year - Rising Star

Continuing Professional Development Scholarship

Sigma Theta Tau International, Delta Xi Chapter Academic Scholarship

### **Publications**

The use of faculty policy teams for advancing policy advocacy and colleagueship

# Jason Fisher

MSN, RN, CCRN | Adjunct Faculty, & Acute Care Nurse Practitioner Student

Dayton, Ohio

# Summary

With over a decade of both business and clinical experience, I am passionate about improving the health and wellness of others while having a positive impact on the larger healthcare system. My background is primarily in perioperative and cardiovascular critical care, with experience across most of the care continuum.

# Experience

Supplemental Health Care
Travel Registered Nurse
January 2016 - Present (4 years 6 months)
Dayton, Ohio, United States

Short-term travel nursing assignments in primarily critical care and perioperative care:

- COVID-ICU, M Health Fairview Bethesda Hospital, Minneapolis, MN (5/2020 to Present)
- ICU, OhioHealth Berger Hospital, Circleville, OH (3/2020 to 5/2020)
- ICU, PCU, M/S, Bon Secours Mercy Health, Cincinnati, OH (2/2019 to 4/2019)
- PACU, M/S, University of Cincinnati Medical Center, Cincinnati, OH (3/2018 to 2/2019)
- Critical Care Hospital Float, TICU, SICU, MICU, NICU, CCU, PACU, ED, M/S, Jackson Memorial Hospital, Miami, FL (1/2016 to 8/2016)

Kent State University
Adjunct Faculty
August 2019 - Present (11 months)
Kent, Ohio

Teaching health care policy online to undergraduate nursing students.

### Cornovus

Founder/Consultant March 2009 - Present (11 years 4 months)

### Dayton, Ohio Area

- Exploring solutions to healthcare challenges.
- Consulting for clients including small businesses, state and federal government.
- Niche experience in mobile and health information technology with generalist experience across industries.

Bon Secours Mercy Health Nurse Manager May 2019 - February 2020 (10 months) Springfield, Ohio, United States

- Responsible for leading 50 team-members caring for patients in a 22-bed PCU.
- Reshaped the culture of the unit through relationship-building, mentorship, restarting shared governance, and cultivating peer-accountability. Reduced nurse turnover from 55% to 0% after my first three months.
- Implemented evidence-based practice initiatives, starting with a published update to the unit's scope of service and standards of care to align with the best evidence, followed by interventions to improve handoffs and care progression.
- Reduced largest monthly supply cost by 80% and alarm fatigue by promoting evidence-based practice initiatives to reduce continuous pulse oximetry monitoring.
- Created structure with new orientation and scheduling processes and materials resulting in improved satisfaction from nurses new to the unit, as well as competency tracking for contracted nurses and staffing forecasts for all inpatient units.

Addison Home Health Services
Interim Administrator & Clinical Director
April 2017 - March 2018 (1 year)

Dayton, Ohio, United States

- Care planning and coordination for an adult patient population while ensuring optimal utilization of resources.
- Built initial budget, forecasts, and business plan while serving as interim administrator and clinical director.

Cleveland Clinic
Registered Nurse
March 2012 - January 2016 (3 years 11 months)
Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

- Served as charge nurse and gained significant experience in critical care, cardiovascular, and electrophysiology nursing care.
- Past chair of the Nursing Research and Evidence-Based Practice Council on main campus, as well as a professional practice committee on the coronary ICU shared governance council. Developed two journal clubs for discussion and appraisal of relevant literature. Participated in nursing informatics journal club and EPIC super-user committee.

### **SNFs**

Licensed Practical Nurse May 2010 - March 2012 (1 year 11 months) Columbus, Ohio Area

- Provided skilled care as a licensed practical nurse (LPN) primarily to clients on short-term stays on rehabilitation units across multiple skilled nursing facilities.
- Supervised teams of up to four nurse aides on rehabilitation, long-term care, and assisted living units.

### OhioHealth

Patient Care Assistant December 2009 - May 2010 (6 months)

Columbus, Ohio, United States

- Built a foundation of patient care skills on a hospital medical-surgical floor.
- Awarded four Power of One awards over first four months for customer service excellence.

### Zebra Mobile (Startup)

Finance, Operations, and Technical Project Manager April 2008 - March 2009 (1 year)

Cincinnati, Ohio

- Developed and led project management processes for the simultaneous development of two software as a service web applications.
- Responsible for managing operations, finances, human resources, and leading the customer support team.
- Constructed company budgets and forecasts, and captured and reported key metrics.
- Built marketing plans for product offerings and worked with teams in executing them.

Ohio Development Services Agency

### Credit Analyst

January 2004 - April 2008 (4 years 4 months)

Columbus, Ohio Area

- Reviewed business plans and analyzed financial statements of small and medium-sized businesses in several industries for financing business expansions, closing transaction up to \$10 million while administering a \$100 million loan fund financing early-stage technology businesses.
- Lead a public-private partnership to direct and prioritize the annual allocation of nearly \$1 billion in tax-exempt private activity bonding authority to emerging industry sectors and development projects.

# Education

Kent State University

Post-Masters Certificate, Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse

Practitioner · (2020 - 2022)

Kent State University

Master's Degree, Nursing (2016 - 2019)

Ohio University

Bachelor's Degree, Nursing · (2012 - 2013)

**Excelsior College** 

Associate of Science - AS, Nursing · (2010 - 2012)

Columbus State Community College

Certificate, Health Information Management Systems · (2009 - 2010)